It's been one week since the Grieving Souls
began operating in the capital of Zebrudia.
I wasn't expecting this.
I can't believe that my
ultimate divine sword,
the Testament Blade,
would break just like that!
I mean, it was a wooden sword...
That's pushing it when
going up against phantoms.
But I never expected to encounter a
cyclops in a level 1 treasure vault...
It was so strong!
Yeah.
Cyclopes are at least a level 4.
At least, that's what it said
in the material I read.
Yup.
A cyclops, you say?!
What the hell are you talking
about, damn rookies?
As if something like that would
ever appear in the Goblin Cave!
Oh, is that it?
Since you're here,
you actually managed to run
away from the cyclops?
Poke, poke.
Hmm?
What's that, girlie?
Look, old-timer.
It's an eyeball!
That's why I told you
to not take the head.
We are now in the golden age
of the treasure hunters!
Amid the sparkling talent on
display in the capital of Zebrudia,
there was one man who stood
out amongst all others!
His name is Krai Andrey.
This is an epic tale
full of glory and agony,
of how he became renowned
for being the leader
of the strongest party he founded
with his childhood friends,
and also the master of the strongest clan!
So how long will this head stay around?
It will eventually turn into
mana material and disappear.
Since it's a phantom.
Episode 03
I Want to Fly Straight Through the Sky
"I Want to Fly Straight Through the Sky."
Let This Grieving Soul Retire
That didn't look like something that
would appear in a level 3 treasure vault.
Sheesh, that thing sure was tough!
There was only one.
We had the numerical advantage.
Oh, yeah. How come
you didn't use your fire?
Oh, well, about that...
What's wrong?
The Purgatorial Sword is out of mana.
What?
Oh.
Because of back then!
I can't charge it myself.
Hey. Maybe it would be better
if we retreated for now...
These conditions are completely
different from what was outlined.
I bet under these circumstances,
the people we're supposed
to rescue are already dead.
We're sticking to the plan.
Not to mention, we haven't
even entered the vault yet.
Hold up.
At the end of the day, surviving
is more important, right?!
If another one of those
things comes at us again...
It seems you are still
confused, Great Greg.
Just Greg is fine.
It seems you are still confused, Greg.
We're not here to collect the dead.
Those people are still alive.
We're executing a level 8's
inscrutable strategy.
Master's decision making is infallible.
The Purgatorial Sword's mana being depleted
must also be a part of Master's plan.
You mean he did it on purpose?
He's telling us not to rely on relics.
Hey, some of them have bows and guns.
So it's not like the one we
encountered was just an outlier.
The White Wolf's Den was
created to suit the size
of the Silver Moon wolf monsters
that originally lived here.
Being so large, they probably can't
move that well inside the den.
So you're saying that rather
than fighting in the open,
we should hurry and get inside.
I'm going in.
If we can get rid of the bows and guns,
the rest should be manageable somehow.
Are you an idiot,
or a dumbass,
or a numpty?
Even without mana, the Purgatorial Sword
is stronger than a regular sword!
Don't do anything rash.
As the leader, it's my duty
to get you all back alive.
What?
This time, Master is counting on me
to act in the capacity of a leader.
Returning home with every single member
alive is essentially the bare minimum.
As Rhuda and I are nimble,
we'll draw the enemy to us first.
Then the two of you assault
their back line from behind.
Their ranged weapons won't
be so scary if we get close.
Even if things turn dangerous,
we won't use anyone as a
shield, or sacrifice them.
Please, let at least Tino be alive!
Even if she has to use the rest
of the party as meat shields!
The enemy outweighs us
considerably in skill.
But we do have one thing going for us.
Teamwork.
All right!
Dammit.
This really is an unreasonable job.
As expected, it's not so difficult to
defeat them with four people on our side.
No matter how strong they are,
the enemy has no concept of cooperation.
Here they come.
We'll cut them to ribbons!
Even though it's an ad-hoc party,
this lineup isn't too bad.
He may have a big mouth,
but Gilbert is decently strong.
Greg has a lot of experience,
so he coordinates well with others.
Rhuda doesn't do anything too flashy,
but as a thief, she's an
expert at locating enemies.
If she hadn't been here,
I wouldn't have been able
to focus on combat.
Every single detail was calculated.
As I thought, Master was right.
Master is a god.
Damn it! You think I'm playing around?!
Are you guys playing around?!
You need to have more guts!
Sorry...
We can barely manage
to keep up with you.
That's it! I'm done!
Gilbert!
It's not like they weren't trying.
Gilbert...
But the gap between us
only kept getting bigger.
I've had enough.
I'm leaving.
Back then, I was so full of anger.
Now I understand
that they were desperate.
I had never even
considered their feelings.
I never knew...
that fighting side by side with
a team could feel this good...
You're not half bad.
I'm finally getting warmed up.
You don't say.
This place sure opened up.
What is it?
There's someone here.
The rescue targets?
No, most likely, it's the boss.
Master's missions usually have a big one.
Shouldn't we run away?
We managed to get this
far without a scratch.
We should be able to
handle the boss, too.
Greg, a big guy like
you shouldn't be so cautious.
Safe missions don't make people grow.
Caution is generally good,
but sometimes you need
to throw it to the wind.
Well, but...
You're not entirely wrong.
Once a hunter reaches level 4,
they can make a fine living just by
completing treasure vaults below their level.
Whenever I thought that I couldn't win,
I stopped engaging the enemy.
This was in no doubt influenced by
seeing many of my friends die.
Despite being in the
hunter biz for so long,
you approached First Steps
because you wanted to change that.
That's...
That is the reason Master
placed you into this party.
What?!
Otherwise, why would he choose
someone he barely knew?
That's right.
Master wanted to save all of you.
That is to say,
Master is a god.
Did you really think Master
put this group together randomly?
He's not the kind to throw spaghetti
at the wall to see what sticks.
All of this has been according
to his inscrutable plan
and elaborate calculations.
Obviously, he's a god.
Uh, so why did he pick me?
Maybe 'cause you've got big boobs?
Hey, wait!
What is that supposed to mean?
Stop playing around.
Let's go beat up that boss already.
Y-Yeah.
Okay.
Jeez.
Wait up!
I can't see Tino anywhere.
Does that mean that I'm too late?
Either way, this relic
goes too damn fast!
What the hell was the creator thinking,
making this thing with no brakes?!
Too fast! Too scary!
I'm gonna die!
So this is... the boss...
He's way too damn big!
He's strong.
Now what?
Do we retreat?
This boss isn't wearing a helmet...
which means that
must be its weak point.
This is one of Master's Thousand Trials.
I will overcome this!
Block one of his blows.
I'll take it from there.
Got it!
All right. Shall we?
Let's go!
So heavy!
I can't see a hint of fear on that girl.
She's amazing.
It broke!
Greg!
She got him!
She did?
She did it...
We win.
Tino, is your leg all right?
It's fine.
I've got a potion.
Damn.
Of all the times for my sword to break...
This just isn't my day.
At least you're alive, old man.
You're damn right.
Thanks, Rhuda.
Sure.
I'm just glad I managed
to get to you in time.
Now all that's left is the rescue.
That's right.
You can have this.
It's better than nothing.
R-Right...
Thank you.
What the hell?
You mean there's more than one boss?!
But it's a boss!
This can't be happening!
Master...
This second helping...
really is too much.
Wh-What do we do?
What do you mean?
We have no choice.
Tino!
We'll run into the
nearest passage on the right.
A passage that narrow will
have a low ceiling, too.
They won't be able to swing
their swords and clubs in there.
He blocked it?!
We'll be the bait.
There's no other option.
Tino, Rhuda.
The two of you should be nimble
enough to break through.
Do whatever you can to escape!
But...
It's better than all of us dying.
Don't dwell on it too much.
It happens all the time.
It's our turn now, is all.
Is this really the only
thing we can do, Master?
Master!
I already told you,
we're not sacrificing anyone.
Tino...
We have to go for their eyes.
I'll do it.
Please back me up.
Take this!
I did it!
Master, I did it!
You did well.
All because of your tutelage.
Master...
Now!
Right.
If we can get him now...
Don't!
Gilbert!
Sorry.
No. My directions
weren't good enough.
You did nothing wrong.
I guess this is it.
Ow, ow, ow...
M-Master?!
I spy a Tino!
Master!
Are they... scared?
Huh?
What is this huge thing?
Too bad.
I've got 17 lives.
So this is a level 8?!
Wh-Whoa...
Master!
I didn't really mean to
show off like that...
But what is this?
What are all these terrifying things?
This is a level 3
treasure vault, right?!
What the—?!
He ate all those attacks, and still...
I mean, yeah. Shooting Rings
are not that powerful.
They're just flashy.
So, once again.
Why bows and guns?!
That doesn't make any sense!
Sure am glad I brought 17 Safety Rings.
I don't even care about
the rescue mission anymore!
I just wanna go home!
I've got no choice.
Now that it's come to this,
I'll take this, and...
Tino, run!
Y-Yes!
You, too!
Yes, sir.
Hey, at this pace,
they'll catch us in no time!
Tino is hurt, you idiot!
Krai's deliberately setting a slower pace
as the rearguard with that in mind!
M-My bad!
What?
I'm running at full tilt here!
Master, that casual kindness reminds
me of the first time we met...
Nobody's coming to save you.
You're on your own.
This'll be over quick.
She'll fetch a good price.
Help...
What the hell?
You two are in the way.
Yup.
It's because you're standing there.
Take that!
Die!
Let's split!
Grieving Souls, eh?!
I won't forget this!
Man, they ran away!
That's fine.
Yup.
Excuse me, but may I know your name?
We're not that special.
I've wanted to join the Grievers ever since.
And Master is... a god!
We made it out...
That was close.
You saved us.
Huh?
Oh. Sure.
M-Master.
Krai, Tino did so well!
If it wasn't for her, I bet
we'd all be dead by now.
Yeah, I can imagine.
Sorry.
How nice would it be if that
word could solve anything.
I-It's okay...
I can tell you did well
just by looking at you.
Master!
She really got beaten up...
Huh? What is it?
Oh, I see.
Uhh, it hurts.
It hurts.
Hold on.
Thank you so much, Master!
It doesn't hurt anymore.
Yup, yup.
I guess he uses a relic for healing.
I need a relic for every single thing
I do. Got a problem with that?!
Krai, did you defeat those bosses?
I did not.
In the moment,
that was the best option.
But that's not what we need to
be thinking about right now.
Anyway, let's walk.
S-Sure.
So now...
The real issue is... Where even are we,
and where is the exit?
Seriously, what do I do?
I'm gonna puke.
Our Krai Andrey forges ahead
with the expectations of the other
four resting on his shoulders.
But isn't he forgetting about the
people who need to be rescued?!
Can our Krai Andrey
actually save them?!
Please tune in again next time!
Hey, yo! Stupid wolves wearing skulls!
By: Tino Shade & Wall Spaghetti Party
A bunch of them came out and gave us grief.
The long, winding White Wolf's Labyrinth.
We have no plan but we forge ahead!
Again, more of those skull jerks!
This is serious trouble!
Huh? What? That can't be!
What happened?
Next time, on Let This Grieving Soul...
...Retire!
Episode 04
The Mysterious Mask Wants to Fight
Please forgive me! Please forgive me! I'm sorry!
"The Mysterious Mask Wants to Fight."